

var quiz = { "JS" : [
	{
		"id" : 1,
		"question" : "Which one of the below is not divide and conquer approach?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Insertion Sort", 
			 "b":" Merge Sort", 
			 "c":"Shell Sort", 
			 "d":"Heap Sort"}
			],
		"answer":"Merge Sort",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 2,
		"question" : "Postfix expression is just a reverse of prefix expression.",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "True", 
			 "b":"False", 
			 }
			],
		"answer":"False",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 3,
		"question" : " Minimum number of moves required to solve a Tower of Hanoi puzzle is",
		"options" : [
			{"a": " 2n^2", 
			 "b":"2n-1", 
			 "c":"2^n-1;"}
			],
		"answer":"2^n-1;",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 4,
		"question" : "Minimum number of spanning tree in a connected graph is",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "n", 
			 "b":"n^n-1",
			 "c":"1",
			 "d":"0"
			}
			],
		"answer":"1",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 5,
		"question" : " Which of the following is example of in-place algorithm?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Bubble Sort", 
			 "b":"Merge Sort",
			 "c":"Insertion Sort",
			 "d":"All of the above",
			}
			],
		"answer":"Merge Sort",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 6,
		"question" : "The number of binary trees with 3 nodes which when traversed in post order gives the sequence A,B,C is ?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "3", 
			 "b":"4",
			 "c":"5",
			 "d":"6",
			}
			],
		"answer":"5",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 7,
		"question" : "node.next -> node.next.next; will make",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "node.next inaccessible", 
			 "b":"node.next.next inaccessible",
			 "c":"this node inaccessible",
			 "d":" none of the above"
			}
			],
		"answer":"node.next inaccessible",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 8,
		"question" : "Which of the following algorithm cannot be desiged without recursion −",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Tower of Hanoi", 
			 "b":"Fibonacci Series",
			 "c":"Tree Traversal",
			 "d":" None of the above ",
			}
			],
		"answer":" None of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 9,
		"question" : "If we choose Prim's Algorithm for uniquely weighted spanning tree instead of Kruskal's Algorithm, then",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "we'll get a different spanning tree.", 
			 "b":"we'll get the same spanning tree.",
			 "c":" spanning will have less edges.",
			 "d":"spanning will not cover all vertices."
			}
			],
		"answer":"we'll get the same spanning tree.",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 10,
		"question" : "Aposterior analysis are more accurate than apriori analysis because −",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "it contains the real data.", 
			 "b":" it assumes all other factors to be dynamic.",
			 "c":"it assumes all other factors to be constant.",
			 "d":" it is a result of reverse-engineering.",
			}
			],
		"answer":" it assumes all other factors to be dynamic.",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 11,
		"question" : "Which of the following points is/are true about Linked List data structure when it is compared with array?",  
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Arrays have better cache locality that can make them better in terms of performance.", 
			 "b":"It is easy to insert and delete elements in Linked List",
			 "c":"Random access is not allowed in a typical implementation of Linked Lists",
			 "d":"The size of array has to be pre-decided, linked lists can change their size any time.",
			 "e":"All of the above"
			}
			],
		"answer":"All of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 12,
		"question" : "Which of the following sorting algorithms can be used to sort a random linked list with minimum time complexity?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Insertion Sort", 
			 "b":"Quick Sort",
			 "c":"Heap Sort",
			 "d":"Merge Sort"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Merge sort",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 13,
		"question" : "In linked list each node contains a minimum of two fields. One field is data field to store the data second field is?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": " Pointer to character", 
			 "b":"Pointer to integer",
			 "c":"Pointer to node",
			 "d":"Node"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Pointer to node",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 14,
		"question" : "What would be the asymptotic time complexity to add a node at the end of singly linked list, if the pointer is initially pointing to the head of the list?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "O(1)", 
			 "b":"O(n)",
			 "c":"θ(n)",
			 "d":"θ(1)"
			}
			],
		"answer":"θ(n)",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 15,
		"question" : "What would be the asymptotic time complexity to insert an element at the front of the linked list (head is known)?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "O(1)", 
			 "b":"O(n)",
			 "c":"O(n^2)",
			 "d":"O(n^3)"
			}
			],
		"answer":"O(1)",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 16,
		"question" : "What would be the asymptotic time complexity to find an element in the linked list?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "O(1)", 
			 "b":"O(n)",
			 "c":"O(n^2)",
			 "d":"O(n^4)"
			}
			],
		"answer":"O(n)",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 17,
		"question" : "What would be the asymptotic time complexity to insert an element at the second position in the linked list?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "O(1)", 
			 "b":"O(n)",
			 "c":"O(n^2)",
			 "d":"O(n^3)"
			}
			],
		"answer":"O(1)",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 18,
		"question" : "The concatenation of two lists can be performed in O(1) time. Which of the following variation of the linked list can be used?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Singly linked list", 
			 "b":"Doubly linked list",
			 "c":"Circular doubly linked list",
			 "d":"Array implementation of list"

			}
			],
		"answer":"Circular doubly linked list",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 19,
		"question" : "Express -15 as a 6-bit signed binary number.",
		"options" : [
			{"a": " 001111", 
			 "b":"101111",
			 "c":"101110",
			 "d":"001110"

			}
			],
		"answer":"101111",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 20,
		"question" : "Which is the predefined method available in Java to convert decimal to binary numbers?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "toBinaryInteger(int)", 
			 "b":"toBinaryValue(int)",
			 "c":"toBinaryNumber(int)",
			 "d":"toBinaryString(int)"
			}
			],
		"answer":"toBinaryString(int)",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 21,
		"question" : "What is the time complexity for converting decimal to binary numbers?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "O(1)", 
			 "b":"O(n)",
			 "c":"O(logn)",
			 "d":"O(nlogn)"
			}
			],
		"answer":"O(logn)",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 22,
		"question" : "To implement a stack using queue(with only enqueue and dequeue operations), how many queues will you need?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "1", 
			 "b":"2",
			 "c":"3",
			 "d":"4"
			}
			],
		"answer":"2",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 23,
		"question" : "Process of inserting an element in stack is called ____________",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Create", 
			 "b":"Push",
			 "c":"Evalution",
			 "d":"Pop"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Push",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 24,
		"question" : " Process of removing an element from stack is called __________",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Create", 
			 "b":"Push",
			 "c":"Evalution",
			 "d":"Pop"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Pop",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 25,
		"question" : "In a stack, if a user tries to remove an element from an empty stack it is called _________",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Underflow", 
			 "b":"Empty collection",
			 "c":"Overflow",
			 "d":"Garbage Collection"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Underflow",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	}
	]
}



var quizApp = function() {

	this.score = 0;		
	this.qno = 1;
	this.currentque = 0;
	var totalque = quiz.JS.length;

	
	this.displayQuiz = function(cque) {
		this.currentque = cque;
		if(this.currentque <  totalque) {
			$("#tque").html(totalque);
			$("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
			$("#next").attr("disabled", false);
			$("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
	
			
			$("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);	
			 $("#question-options").html("");
			for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
			  if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
		
				$("#question-options").append(
					"<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
					"<label class='form-check-label'>" +
							  "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option'   id='q"+key+"' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
								  quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
							 "</span></label>"
				);
			  }
			}
		}
		if(this.currentque <= 0) {
			$("#previous").attr("disabled", true);	
		}
		if(this.currentque >= totalque) {
				$('#next').attr('disabled', true);
				for(var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
					this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
				}
			return this.showResult(this.score);	
		}
	}
	
	this.showResult = function(scr) {
		$("#result").addClass('result');
		$("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr  + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
		for(var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
			var res;
			if(quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
					res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
			} else {
				res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
			}
			$("#result").append(
			'<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
			'<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
			'<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
			
			'</div>' 
			
			);
			
		}
	}
	
	this.checkAnswer = function(option) {
		var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
		option = option.replace(/\</g,"&lt;")   //for <
		option = option.replace(/\>/g,"&gt;")   //for >
		option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")

		if(option ==  quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
			if(quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
				quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
				quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
		}
		} else {
			quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
		}
		
	}	
	 
	this.changeQuestion = function(cque) {
			this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
			this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);	
			
	}
	
}


var jsq = new quizApp();

var selectedopt;
	$(document).ready(function() {
			jsq.displayQuiz(0);		
		
	$('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function(e) {

			//var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
			$(this).prop("checked", true);
				selectedopt = $(this).val();
		});
		
			
			 
	});

	
	
	
	$('#next').click(function(e) {
			e.preventDefault();
			if(selectedopt) {
				jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
			}
			jsq.changeQuestion(1);
	});	
	
	$('#previous').click(function(e) {
		e.preventDefault();
		if(selectedopt) {
			jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
		}
			jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
	});	



